Daniel J. Mason

Altamonte Springs, FL 32701 | (813) 528-6550 | daniel.j.msn@gmail.com |

Github: www.github.com/Daniel-J-Mason **Website/Portfolio**: www.all-thing.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Eager Java developer with a passion for backend development and Linux. I currently have 3 years of experience in Software Development and 5 years of experience in Mechanical Engineering. I have used various languages to design and develop desktop and web applications across multiple APIs, frameworks, and databases. I am seeking to transition into full time software development and am confident that my experience will lead to meaningful contributions within your organization. Please view my Github and Website/Portfolio (linked at the top)!

SKILLS

<u>Languages:</u> <u>Frameworks and Libraries:</u> <u>Tools:</u>

Java, Python Spring, JavaFX, PostgreSQL, MariaDB Linux, Git, Docker, Maven, Gradle, Liquibase

WORK EXPERIENCE

Application Development (Work Project)

Rev Group Inc. | Orlando, FL | Jun 2021 – Current |

- Propose, design, and implement internal JavaFX applications for engineering departments and management.
- Develop and deploy a custom search application to find all engineering-related files on the network; App searches all parts, part family tables, and order/contract specific files in order to improve engineering department efficiency.
- Produce additional search module to find all units containing parts to assist with error containment and design.
- Create Transmittal Review application to efficiently compare engineering design packages and CAD assembly parts in order to optimize design time, improve self checks/reviews, and minimize production errors.
- Develop, maintain, and push new releases of applications to improve engineering design and review processes.

Senior Mechanical Engineer

Rev Group Inc. | Orlando, FL | Apr 2023 – Current |

- Lead responsible for the continued design and development of the ambulance Wheeled Coach brand.
- Train/mentor several junior engineers through technical guidance, peer review, and hands-on training.
- Interpret contracts and specifications to determine feasibility and advise on customer requests.
- Improve ISO controlled engineering review documentation and release multiple engineering change notices.

Mechanical Engineer II

Rev Group Inc. | Orlando, FL | Mar 2018 - Apr 2023 |

- Designed over 300 ambulance exteriors across six independent brands for body fabrication.
- Provided solutions to critical production issues through hands-on analysis of ambulances on the floor.
- Reviewed final assembly release packages to ensure design quality prior to production start.

OPEN SOURCE DEVELOPMENT

Backend Java Developer

Elite Dangerous Pilots Network (In-progress) | April 2023 - Current

Github: https://github.com/ed-pilots-network

- Collaborate with a team of senior backend engineers to develop REST backend for the Elite Dangerous Pilots Network (EDPN) web application using: Spring, Kafka, Liquibase, Gradle, Git, Mybatis, PostgreSQL and Docker.
- Responsible for significant contribution to Spring stack and PostgreSQL schema design.
- Lead organization of backend development team proposals, objectives, and requirements.
- Communicate/present expectations with frontend and operation leads for the web application.
- Utilize code review to improve code quality and uphold design standards/architecture.
- Create unit tests to check application modules for functionality and as part of the deployment cycle.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering—University of Central Florida Orlando FL | December 2017